SAMUEL OLANIYAN

Calgary, AB | 403-888-1568 | olaniyansamuel2015@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/samuel-olaniyan/ https://www.samuelolaniyan.tech/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A Passionate and highly motivated full-stack software developer with over two years of experience collaborating with web designers and using a variety of programming languages and tools to develop efficient, reliable, and accessible products. An exceptional problem-solver with years of finance experience, allowing him to bring a unique blend of software engineering and financial knowledge to build scalable products on time and within budget.

Skills & Expertise

Programming languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C#.
 Front-end stack: ReactJS, Tailwind, Bootstrap
 Back-end stack: NodeJS, Microsoft .Net, Django
 Database management: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.
 Cloud frameworks: Amazon web services(AWS), Azure

Other tools: Git, GitHub, Docker, Jira

• Interpersonal Skills: Communication, Time management, and Problem-solving.

Relevant Work Experience

Full Stack Developer

Nov 2020 - Dec 2022

MerchBro Enterprises, Lagos, Nigeria

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, develop, and implement web-based applications using a range of technologies including React, Node.js, and PostgreSQL.
- Developed RESTful APIs to provide access to application data and integrate with third-party services.
- Designed and maintained databases, ensuring data consistency and security
- Assessed the technical feasibility of UI designs and ensured the final output is aligned with the organization's branding to ensure consistent product quality across all applications.
- Implemented DevOps practices to improve the deployment and testing processes
- Trained new team members and participated in code reviews to ensure high-quality code.

Senior Treasury Analyst

Sep 2017 -Nov 2020

Access Bank PLC, Lagos, Nigeria

- Monitored and analyzed the company's cash flow, identifying opportunities for improvement and implementing solutions to optimize cash management.
- Developed and maintained strong relationships with banks and financial institutions, negotiating favourable terms for loans and other financial instruments.
- Conducted detailed financial analysis to support decision-making and strategic planning.
- Led a team of five that contributed more than 20% to the organization's revenue in 2021 (the highest single contribution by any team).

Education

MSc. Information Technology

University of Aberdeen, United Kingdom

Jan 2022 - Mar 2023

• Coursework included enterprise & advanced software development, software project management, web development, information security, human-computer interaction database management and big data.

BSc. Chemical Engineering

University of Ilorin, Nigeria

Nov 2010 - Aug 2015

Projects

- E-Ledger Accounting software (MerchBro Enterprises, Lagos, Nigeria)
 - Collaborated with a team to design and develop the user interface for a simple accounting software. The software provides a real-time overview of the financial position of the business, as well as cash flow projections for future periods. This app was built using React, NodeJS and PostgreSQL
- Child-Adult Relationship Observation Tool (University of Aberdeen)

Led the development of video-coding software for Mellow Parenting, an NGO focused on improving child-parent relationships. The software enables researchers to observe and code interactions between mothers and their young children. Developed the application using the MERN stack, which includes MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js.

- Personal projects
 - o Available at https://www.samuelolaniyan.tech/

Certifications

Microsoft Power Platform Fundamentals (PL-900)

Professional Scrum Master (PSM1), Scrum.Org

Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner, IBM

Jul 2020